<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whitman College and Northwest Archives</title>
    <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Whitman College and Northwest Archives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 18:27:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://library.whitman.edu/archives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Archives Access Policy, Summer 2023</title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/access-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 18:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/access-policy/</guid>
      <description>[Updated June 26. 2023]
   Open hours are 9am-noon and 1pm-4pm, Monday through Friday.
  Appointments are required and must be made at least 24 hours in advance.
 Appointments allow us time to have materials prepared for you in advance and to locate other relevant resources.    Appointments can be made online; by emailing archives@whitman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walla Walla Coronavirus Stories</title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/walla-walla-coronavirus-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 23:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/walla-walla-coronavirus-stories/</guid>
      <description>Documenting our Lives during the COVID-19 Pandemic 
Whitman College and Northwest Archives is creating a digital archive of the Walla Walla community’s experiences during the COVID-19 pandemic. As our community begins to reopen, it is important to reflect on our experiences of the pandemic, including our experiences at work and school, our social and family interactions, and the changes to our routines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Projects</title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/digital-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/digital-projects/</guid>
      <description> Arminda: Digital Archives Whitman Coronavirus Stories Walla Walla Coronavirus Stories LGBTQ+ Oral History Project Portraits of the past Reading 36 Million Words: Text Mining the Pioneer  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruction and Tours</title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/instruction-and-tours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/instruction-and-tours/</guid>
      <description>Class Sessions in the Archives Faculty are encouraged to incorporate materials from the Archives into their teaching. There are multiple, scalable options for curricular use of collections and the Archivists are available to work with you to achieve your pedagogical goals. These include:
 A single class visit to the archives to orient students to the collections and space A thematic visit to the archives, with selections on a particular topic, subject, or theme An assignment designed around collections that requires out-of-class student visits to the archives An entire class or syllabus built around archival collections  In all these scenarios, our instruction focuses both on enabling students to find and use collections, and developing their skills in analyzing and interpreting primary sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information for Researchers</title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/research-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/research-services/</guid>
      <description>Reading Room Procedures The Reading Room is open from 9am-noon, 1pm-4pm, Monday through Friday. Appointments are required and must be made at least 24 hours in advance. Appointments can be made online.
The following guidelines are required for all patrons working in the Reading Room:
 Masks are optional for patrons using materials in the Reading Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Archives</title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/about/</guid>
      <description>Mission and History The Whitman College and Northwest Archives curates materials that document the history of Whitman College and the Walla Walla region as well as rare books and other special collections housed in Penrose Library. The archives collects, preserves, provides access to, and promotes the use of these materials for teaching, learning, and research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore our Collections</title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/explore-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/explore-collections/</guid>
      <description>Northwest Manuscripts Collection WCNA acknowledges that we exist upon the traditional homeland of the Cayuse, Umatilla, Walla Walla and Nez Perce Peoples. WCNA collects and solicits donations of manuscripts and records from individuals and organizations of significance to the history and present of the Walla Walla region and the inland Pacific Northwest. Strengths of our manuscript collections include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/archives-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/archives-announcement/</guid>
      <description>The archives are available to researchers by appointment only. You can schedule an appointment [here](https://wcna.youcanbook.me).
We will be closed June 24-28.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
